hello and welcome you're watching
business today i'm sakshi patra well
icici lombard general insurance company
india's leading private general
insurance company has reported its q4
earnings and to discuss the fine print
and the outlook from here on i'm joined
by the company's md and ceo mr
bhargavdas gupta mr dhaas thank you so
much for taking the time out and joining
us on business today so let me kick
start by asking you first we have seen
uh some dent on your profit this time
around in the quarter ten percent on a
year on year drop what has really caused
this dead are there any reasons that are
only particular to this quarter or uh
you know is there a problem that could
continue going forward from your respect
thanks uh for having me sakshi uh to
answer your question there are two
reasons why the numbers are what you see
in the quarter in terms of growth we are
very happy with the growth momentum
picking up and if you look at our
numbers month or month while for the
quarter we've grown in line with the
market for the month of march we've
grown uh much more than the market
okay now there are two reasons why this
has
you know what your question you know
that you have the two aspects to answer
that one is that
we had about 27 crores of hit because of
covet wave 3
which is you know kind of a one-off uh
compared to what we had the previous
year
but the second and the bigger reason is
that in insurance the accounting norm is
that when you write a business when you
source a business the sourcing cost is
booked up front so you take the full hit
of the cost and you know including the
distribution cost commission etcetera
that you pay you book it up front and
the income is taken over the 12 month or
the period of the policy whatever may be
the appropriate number now in our case
it's largely 12 months because these are
annual policies so when you have a very
high growth in the month of march you're
taking the full cost of the you know
business in that month but the income
gets spread over the next 12 months now
when you look at the combined ratio that
uh combined ratio adjusts for that so
that's why we look at the combined issue
because that tells you what is the
business that you've written what are
the kind of profits that you earn over
the period so if you see the combined
ratio for the company from let's say you
know last year last quarter 104 odd
percent this this water will come down
to 103.
absolutely i also wanted to ask you on
the elevated operating expenses this
time around uh do you foresee the
elevated expenses even going forward
into the next few quarters
so the expenses again if you look at on
a quarter on quarter basis we are seeing
a healthy friend in terms of improvement
uh again largely the operating expenses
are high because as i explained you kind
of spend all the money that you had to
in terms of sourcing the business
earnings will happen over 12 months
okay and so premium growth for you has
grown 34 this quarter also in fy 22 the
gross direct premium income is up 28 on
a year on your basis could you share
with us the outlook on the premium
collections and are you also looking at
any form of price increase for the
retail products in the near future
uh so when you look at compare the
numbers that you compared with last year
and this year it's not completely
comparable because we had the
integration with the party axa business
that we
acquired that happened in this year so
that is not in the base while the party
access numbers are
there for us in the base so if you take
that out
assume the bhartiyaksa numbers are added
to our base last year our group shared
lower than five percent so it's not that
high as you're talking about but if you
look at the month of
march the growth is very very good even
with a base added to last year
so but coming to your question on the
outlook on on growth we are very
optimistic
look uh i think one thing that we've all
learned is that it's very become very
difficult to predict the environment
given the global uncertainties
absolutely we're all hoping that
pandemic pandemic is behind us but the
geopolitics is a new uh unknown in a
sense
now assuming that things are similar to
what we are seeing globally
you know and we are obviously predicting
inflation we are predicting interest
rates going up globally uh because of
the uh you know conflict that we've seen
in ukraine
keeping that in mind we still are very
optimistic about our growth uh for for
this year both from a top line
perspective and profit perspective
anything new that happens which we are
not seeing today is the uncertainty that
you cannot cannot predict
uh so overall
you know in the current context very
optimistic about uh our next year uh
coming to uh your question on price hike
look uh you know in in insurance at
least in in health which is more
relevant for people because health care
costs have gone up uh we don't take
price increases just because of one
event which is for example in in the
year gone by covet
if you look at the industry
and i want to make this point to
all of you viewers we are one industry
which took more than 25 000 crore hit
because of covet that's the number of
claims that the industry collectively
has paid we as isis lombard we've paid
about 550 crores similar to our market
share in health
now unlike any other industry which has
had this kind of a impact
we've not gone to anyone asking for
support
we've not gone to government asking for
subsidy or some you know
or some money against this and by the
way 25 000 crores if you compare with
the industry profits industry makes
about four to five thousand crores of
profits it's much bigger
is five years of profit that we've kind
of uh paid out
so
but still coming back to your question
that doesn't mean that we are going to
increase rates at least in isis loan but
we are not looking at retail pricing
because this we are hoping is one event
one-off event it's not you know
something that we expect to see every
year
what we do look at however is health
clearing healthcare inflation and that
has been elevated and that is what
worries us a bit more rather than just
one of google dreams
okay so going forward which segments
will be your key growth drivers in terms
of say revenues or even market share
for us we believe health will continue
to grow fast if you look at the year
gone by health for the industry in
health category grew at roughly over 25
uh
i mean for the quarter number is a bit
lower because of base effect but even
with this elevated base we believe
health insurance will continue to grow
in india and we believe that our growth
in the health segment will be faster
than the industry
we are a bit uncertain because of this
issues with the supply side which is a
bit unpredictable but we are optimistic
that we've had two years of very slow
motor numbers as a country uh fresh
motor sales we are hopeful that that
will uh you know
we'll see some turnaround this year if
that happens motor will also start going
well we are also quite
happy with the overall commercial lines
business the corporate segment in india
i mean the infrastructure investments
that we are seeing we are seeing good
growth in project insurance so all of
these lines look uh look positive for
next year
okay since you talked about motor
insurance i want to talk about the
latest concern that we are all uh you
know grappling with and that is on the
electric vehicles catching fire from an
insurance perspective how are you
looking at these instances and uh what
is uh going to be a possible resolution
here is there going to be a you know
major concern going forward uh you know
elongated concern or will this be uh
very easily tackled how do you really
see that
actually this is an important issue but
yeah i would want to look at it
from two lens one is a long term and we
believe ev is the
is the you know is a choice for the
future uh we need to move to electric
vehicles
of course and from a short term these
are issues that need to be addressed and
i think we you know the
minister has also talked about that you
know recalls etc that's the right thing
to do i think we have to design for
quality
uh that's what we as an insurer would
want
uh when these things happen it obviously
comes as a as a claim to us uh
thankfully we the portfolio that we have
and we have a very large share of ev
business uh almost a quarter of the two
wheeler evs are insured by us we've not
had too many cases because we've
probably selected the better uh you know
we've had one case you know in aggregate
that i am aware of at this point in time
so we've not had too many hits but i
think principally what you're saying is
absolutely important we need to have
quality because this is uh you know this
is the choice for the future uh for the
planet and we have to support this
absolutely so also since you said that
it has been a major part of the concern
in the last two odd years especially the
last year how we talked about that you
know such a high portion of your profits
like almost five years of profits for
the industry uh were given away in the
kind of uh you know surgeon claims and
everything how are you preparing for a
fourth wave and consecutive waves and is
that going to be a major uh unknown uh
that you are keeping uh you know in your
uh you know outlook that you know this
is something that you have to keep aside
that this much hit you could have to
give you know because of uncertainty
yeah so actually again you know these
are uh things that is very difficult to
predict is what we've seen
we are uh however cautiously hopeful
optimistic and you know if you look at
the wave three uh the while there were
numbers but the severity was much lower
we are hopeful that even if another wave
comes and there are some early signs
that in some pockets there are increases
etcetera we are watching it very very
closely
but even here this time round as well we
are not seeing very high severity of
claims which needs hospitalization so
one of the things that we did when covet
came in the you know right in the first
wave
we launched our home care service
we said that you know if you with on a
cashless basis with our trusted
partners we will provide you home-based
care and that is i think a win-win for
everyone because no one wants to rush to
a hospital unnecessary unnecessarily
if you need if it's a mild infection you
can take uh treatment at home it's on a
cashless basis so that we don't want to
have any misuse of the service
but we are happy to provide that and we
would walk you know kind of encourage
people to take those services if need if
required
okay so as an industry what is uh the
kind of growth outlook that you have for
cfi 23 and for yourself if you could
share some numbers with us if you have
any projections that you've kept for in
your mind
look this year the industry grew at
about 11 in aggregate we think the next
year it will be slightly higher than
that but still in the low teens is our
estimate because of the uncertainties
that we've talked about and the base
effect on the health side
our expectation is that we will grow
faster than this i'm talking about this
without the crop because crop it's a bit
unpredictable because some states are
withdrawing from the scheme etc but the
rest of the industry is what i'm talking
about we expect to grow faster than the
industry next year
okay and last question sir i wanted to
ask you uh are there any opportunities
in the inorganic space that you're
looking at for further growth momentum
into your business
so as you know we just did one we you
know parties business got integrated
this year as i said uh we are we always
look at opportunities and the
opportunities make sense for our
shareholders we will look at but there's
nothing that i can specifically talk
about right now are there any businesses
of reliance capital that you would be
looking at when something if and when
something happens definitely we'll share
it with you okay so when many many
thanks for joining us and sharing the
insights and the fine print of your
results all the very best to you for the
coming quarters as well many thanks for
joining in thank you
[Music]
if you like the video do like comment
share and subscribe